ANNE-LAURE FRÉANT

Software technical writer

BACKGROUND

Professional with 15 years of experience in the tech sector as a technical content specialist, first in Canada for the travel startup <u>Hopper</u> and then in France for various public institutions (French Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Prime Minister Services <u>Etalab</u>).

I evolved from editorial project management, UX, and content writing towards full-time technical writing in 2020. I gained lots of experience joining the <u>ContentSquare</u> Knowledge Management Team in 2022 for a six months full-time contract as a technical writer. Since then, I work on short and long-term contracts for SaaS companies and startups on creating user guides (<u>QuanticFy</u>, <u>Djust</u>, <u>Hyperline</u>), developers portals (<u>Quable</u>, Akeneo), or both (<u>Wefox</u>) to adjust wording and UX writing on top of writing the documentation.

SKILLS

- · API and SaaS technical writing
- · Markdown, JSON, YML
- Github, versioning tools
- CMS & Doc-as-code processes (Readme, Docusaurus, Retype, Mintlify, etc.)
- JIRA, Notion, Trello, Slack
- Basic HTML & CSS, javascript
- Basic command line
- Knowledge base (Confluence)
- · Postman and API testing
- · Open API spec review
- Bilingual french / english

PORTFOLIO

https://tech.annelaurefreant.xyz/

CONTACT

Cell: +33 7 81 85 42 73

Email: annelaure.freant@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Technical writer (freelance) (2023-today)

Remote in Europe

- Developer portal writing / update or migration
- User center writing or updating
- Chatbot content writing and testing
- Open API spec testing and editing
- Clients in the field of e-commerce, PIM solutions, insurance portals, billing solutions, digital marketing...

Technical writer / Knowledge manager (2022-2023)

Contentsquare - Knowledge Management Team, France

- Writing and updating product content on Confluence
- Gathering knowledge from SME and product managers
- Writing release notes and contributing to the data portal's evolutions

Data editor (2020-2021)

Prime Minister Services - Etalab (in charge of data.gouv.fr), France

- Enriching and updating the data.gouv.fr platform documentation
- Updating datasets descriptions, metadata and related content
- Writing the platform newsletter, posting dataset updates on social media

UX and technical writer (2015-2020)

Ministry of Foreign Affairs, France

- Consultant for the building, testing and maintaining of a new digital governmental service to help French citizen with reentry from abroad
- UX writing, information architecture, content writing
- Writer of a 100 pages book and of a blog dedicated to reentry

Technical Content Team Lead (2011-2014)

Hopper.com (Montreal, Canada)

- Data entry, testing and technical content curation
- In charge of recruiting, managing and training a team of 10 data entry parttime employees. Tracking metrics. Reporting to CEO.
- In charge of editorial projects like the early Hopper Research Blog along with the lead data scientist

Research assistant (2010-2012)

Geography department - University of Quebec in Montreal

EDUCATION

Sciencespo Paris - Post-Master - School of Public Affairs Obtained in 2021

University of Quebec in Montreal (UQAM)- Master - Social Sciences
Obtained in 2008